(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-13T02:03:39.610764",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ある国に ロバの娘がいました
In a certain country, there was a donkey's daughter.
周りから見た彼女は それはそれは恵まれて見えました
To those around her, she seemed so very blessed.
ですが 彼女の心は 決して豊かではありません
But her heart was not rich at all.
決められた人形のような生活 本当の私はなんだろう
Living like a prescribed doll, I wonder what the real me is.
大きな大きな犬がいました
There was a big, big dog.
周りを見渡すと みんな小さく愛される犬ばかり
Looking around, everyone was just small, beloved dogs.
自分だけ大きな姿に大きなど声
Only she had a large form and a loud voice.
怖がらないで一緒に遊ぼうよ
Don't be scared, let's play together.
とてもかっこつけがりの猫がいました
There was a very pretentious cat.
みんなからは嘘つき呼ばわりされています
Everyone calls her a liar.
本当はみんなを楽しませたいだけなのに
Even though she just wants to make everyone happy,
おもしろそうなことが大好きなだけさ
she just loves things that seem fun.
毎日仕事があってうらやましいでしょう
You must be envious of having work every day,
楽しくて愉快な農場さ
a fun and cheerful farm.
だけど毎日同じことの繰り返し
But it's the repetition of the same thing every day.
もっと私が輝ける場所があるんじゃないか
Isn't there a place where I can shine brighter?
天下の大泥棒 金銀財宝に目がありません
A world-class thief with no eyes for gold or silver.
でも悪いことはしたいんじゃない
But it's not that I want to do bad things.
貧しいみんなを笑顔にしたいだけなのに
I just want to make the poor people smile,
自分も笑顔になれたらどれだけいいのかな
how wonderful it would be if I could smile too.
大きな悩みを抱えたロバたち
Donkeys carrying big worries,
君たちの物語が今 ここから始まっていくのです
your story is now beginning from here.
音楽 それは私たちの人生に彩りを 勇気を
Music, it brings color and courage to our lives,
そして夢を与えてくれる不思議な魔法
and a mysterious magic that gives us dreams.
これはそんな音楽の力を信じた動物たちの
This is the story of animals who believed in the power of music...
ねえ 考えてもいいよ
Hey, you don't even have to think about it.
口先じゃ分かり合えないの
We can't understand each other just with words.
この音には今は乗ろうよ
Let's ride this sound right now.
忘れないでいたいよ
I want to keep remembering it.
身体は無彩色レイドバック
Our bodies are monochrome laid-back,
ただうねる雨音でグルーヴ
grooving simply to the sound of rolling rain.
ずっと二人で暮らそうよ この夜の隅っこで
Let's live together forever in the corner of this night.
ねえ 不甲斐ない僕らに 誘ったのは君じゃないの
Hey, wasn't it you who invited us, us good-for-nothings?
理屈だけじゃつまらないわ まだ時間が惜しいの
Logic alone is boring, and I still begrudge the time.
練り歩く景色を真空パック 踏み鳴らす足音でグルーヴ
Vacuum-packing the strolling scenery, grooving to the stamping footsteps.
まるで僕らはブレーメン たった二人だけのマーチ
We're just like Bremen, a march of just the two of us.
決められたタスク 決められた笑顔で
With prescribed tasks and a prescribed smile,
決められた人生を歩くの
walking down a prescribed life.
何が私で何が私じゃないか
What is me, and what is not me?
さっぱりわからない
I have no idea at all.
手の物を捨てて 歌を歌えば
If I throw away what's in my hands and sing a song,
私は 本当の私になる
I will become my true self.
虹の入り江 森のカリブー
The rainbow inlet, the forest caribou—
どこでもゆける 何にでもなれる
I can go anywhere, I can become anything,
歌の世界なら
if it's in the world of song.
石油の国の皆様、この度はブレーメンミュージックフェスを開催致します！
Everyone in the oil kingdom, welcome to the Bremen Music Festival!
様々な世界の様々な物語が集まる歌の祭典。これよ、あなただけのお気に入りの音楽を見つけてください！
A festival of songs gathering various stories from various worlds. Find your favorite music here!
私、決めたわ。
I've decided.
ブレーメンへ行こう 本当の自分を見つけよう
Let's go to Bremen and find our true selves.
世界を変える私だけの 歌を探して
Searching for the song that is uniquely mine to change the world.
歌を探して
Searching for the song.
ところで ブレーメンって どっちに行けばいいの？ こっち？ あっち？
By the way, which way should we go to Bremen? This way? That way?
ワン！チャッ！
Woof! Cha!
あー また驚かせちゃった
Ah, I surprised you again.
本当は遊びたかっただけ
I really just wanted to play.
チョービリー 声が大きくて
Cho-Billy, with such a loud voice,
チョービリー 時間が強くて
Cho-Billy, with such strong time,
周りと違うだけで 誰かを困らせてばかりの だめなやつさ
just being different, always troubling someone—such a useless fellow.
あなた とっても素敵な声を持っているのに
You have such a wonderful voice, yet...
そうかな 声が大きすぎて みんなを驚かせちゃうんだ
Is that so? My voice is too big and always surprises everyone.
もう一度 聞かせてみて
Let me hear it one more time.
それじゃ今度は 音楽に合わせて
Then this time, let's match it with the music!
いいかい？吠えて！
Ready? Howl!
ワン！
Woof!
２回吠えて！
Howl twice!
ワン！ワン！
Woof! Woof!
ほら すべて綺麗でしょ
Look, isn't everything beautiful?
重なれば どんなメロディだって
When they overlap, no matter what melody,
居場所を見つけて 響き始める ミュージック
music starts to resonate, finding its place.
ブレーメンへ行こう この声使えばできること
Let's go to Bremen! Whatever we can do using this voice,
きっとあるはずだから 行こう 一緒に
I'm sure it's out there, so let's go together!
さあ寄っていらっしゃい 見ていらっしゃい
Come on in and take a look!
これより語るは甚だしき勇者の危機一髪な冒険譚
Now, I shall tell the tale of a hero's outrageous near-death adventure.
家まで送ってもらいたいのに
Even though I want you to walk me home,
今夜満たされたいのよ
I want to be fulfilled tonight.
できれば君にちょっと濡らして欲しいのよ
If possible, I want you to get me a little wet.
酔いで寄りたいのよ
I want to get drunk and snuggle close,
ごまかしてキスしたいのよ
Play it off and kiss you.
君といたいよ 暗くてぬるい部屋で
I want to be with you in a dark, lukewarm room.
なんかすごそう
"Sounds amazing"—
ってどういう意味？ 朝まで待たせてお年寄りに説教を譲ったってこと？
What does that mean? That you made them wait till morning and left the scolding to an elderly person?
さあ 艶やかな勇者に 勝算を
Now, what are the odds for this glamorous hero?
奏でよう
Let's play!
でも 決まって
But surely...
ほら吹き回り 現実越えたクソ雑魚が
Look at this loudmouth, pathetic weakling surpassing reality—
突き通せた
Piercing through it!
美しいのに つまりそれって
Even though it's beautiful, meaning that—
ともに奏でよ まだ見ぬゲスどものメロディを
Let's play together the melodies of unseen scumbags.
はるか異国の地 開かれる歌劇
In a faraway foreign land, the opera opens.
歌うというのか 面白い新たな冒険が
You say you'll sing? A fun, new adventure—
よろしいわ 勝ち気らをささげよ
Very well, offer up your spirited selves!
ブレメーへ行こう 嘘がもっと輝ける
Let's go to Bremen, where lies can shine even brighter.
それが音楽だから行こう 一緒に
That's what music is, so let's go together!
ブレメーへ行こう 嘘がもっと
Let's go to Bremen, where lies can shine—
輝ける それが音楽だから行こう一緒に
Even brighter! That's what music is, so let's go together!
一番いい役をやりましょう 誰よりも悲しくて殺せる役を
Let's play the best role, a role sadder and more fatal than anyone else's.
四角い海の果てでも代わる代わるは人様演じている事それさえも忘れる世界
Even at the edge of the square sea, people take turns acting—a world where we forget even that we are acting.
みんな籠の中の鳥 いつか抜け出す日夢見て やっと手にしたその時大空へと戸惑う mysterious
All birds in cages, dreaming of the day they'll break free. When they finally grasp it, they're bewildered towards the vast sky, mysterious.
名前をあげて安心させましょう カットはかからない あなたの mysterious
Let's mention names to reassure. Cuts won't be called, your mysterious.
星座を渡り紡ぎ 空へと逃げ仰せても 身体には懐かしさ 咽び捨てようもない ねぇねぇ
Even if we cross constellations and escape up to the sky, there's nostalgia in our bodies we can't choke down and throw away, hey, hey.
時計のない国で 誰も要らないこの街で 熱い雪を降らす青い太陽
In a land without clocks, in a city where no one is needed, a blue sun rains down hot snow.
窓もドアも壁もなく思い描く不死の鳥 間違いも答えもない自由へと彷徨う mysterious
With no windows, doors, or walls, the immortal bird we imagine wanders toward freedom with no mistakes or answers, mysterious.
ひしめく羽を弾ませ 守るのは邪な清らかさ
Guarding the crowded feathers is a gentle purity,
抱きしめられては飛び立つ 白紙に沈め墨たち 硬い水面泳ぐ髪
Embraced and taking flight. Sinking into blank paper, the ink stands out; hair swims on the solid water surface.
通う息吹道連れに 諦めの帳ごふき 飛ぶ飛ば来い宵闇
With passing breaths as companions, wiping away the curtain of resignation, flying, flying, come, evening darkness.
手折られた翼羽で 信じた呪いは願いは祈りは入れ墨 ひひとひらの仕草 mysterious
With severed wings, the curse we believed in, the wish, the prayer, a tattoo—a single gesture, mysterious.
神や仏と悪魔のお友達 いてもいなくても私は mysterious あなたの mysterious
Friends with gods, buddhas, and demons; whether they're there or not, I'm mysterious, your mysterious.
さあ一番いい役をやりましょう 星座渡り紡ぎ 空へと逃げ仰せても 身体には懐かしさ
Now, let's play the best role! Even if we cross constellations and escape up to the sky, there's nostalgia in our bodies—
時計のない国で 誰も要らないこの街で 熱い雪を降らす青い太陽
In a land without clocks, in a city where no one is needed, a blue sun rains down hot snow.
窓もドアも壁も風もなく 思い描く不死の鳥 間違いも答えもない 自由へと彷徨う mysterious
With no windows, doors, walls, or wind, the immortal bird we imagine wanders toward freedom with no mistakes or answers, mysterious.
ひしめく羽を弾ませ 守るのは 邪な清らかさ 抱きしめられては飛び立つ
Guarding the crowded feathers is a gentle purity, embraced and taking flight.
守るのは横島ぬしよだからさ 抱きしめられては飛び立つ
Protecting it is wickedness itself, embraced and taking flight.
あふれしに沈め墨たち 硬いみなも泳ぐ髪 かよういる...
Sinking into overflowing ink, hair swimming on the solid water surface, passing breaths...
今日は絶好調…そのはずでした過去形
Today's going great... or so I thought, past tense.
天気予報ド外面 ドア閉まるバス 憂鬱なmonday
Weather forecast missed, bus door closing, gloomy Monday.
なんて不条理文句 誰行き？hah…
Such absurd complaints, where is this headed? Hah...
八つ当たりは問題外
Taking it out on others is out of the question.
どうしようもないこと多すぎeveryday
Too many helpless things every single day,
現実は手強い
Reality is tough.
だけど試練の向こうへ
But beyond these trials,
ため息ついてここから
Letting out a sigh, right from here
立ち上がれたらまた
If we can stand back up, once again
なにかが始まる
Something will begin.
let's get it going now! going now!
がむしゃら気味にどこへだって繰り出して
Recklessly venturing out anywhere,
胸張って楽しんじゃおうup・down
Puffing out our chests to enjoy the ups and downs.
say everyone, going now! going now!
踊乱らしちゃえば
If we just shake things up,
ああ、そうそう波乱万丈 大体の運命
Ah, yes, full of ups and downs, most of our fate
変えてくのは自分だって――キミは知ってる
Is changed by ourselves—you already know that.
一番いい役をやりにいこう
Let's go play the best role!
やりましょう
Let's do it!
頭でわかっては嘆いた
I understood it in my head and sighed,
転がっていく様子を嘲った
Mocking how things kept tumbling down.
寂しいとか愛とかわかんない 人間の形は投げ出したんだ
Not knowing loneliness or love, I threw away human form.
抱えきれない言葉だらけの存在証明を
Proof of existence made only of words I couldn't hold,
この小さな劇場から出らんない 気づいたら最後逃げ出したい
I can't leave this small theater; before I knew it, I wanted to flee.
僕らが全員演じていたんだ
We were all acting it out,
エンドロールに向かっていくんだ
Heading toward the end credits.
さあ 皆必死に役を演じて 傍観者なんていないのさ
Come on, everyone plays their role desperately; there are no bystanders.
「ワタシ」なんてないの どこにだって居ないよ
There is no "me," nowhere to be found.
ずっと僕は何者にもなれなくて 僕ら今さざめき合って
I could never become anyone at all, as we now murmur together,
延長戦サレンダーして メーデー淡い愛想
Surrendering in overtime, Mayday, faint friendliness,
垂れ流し言の愛憎 dramaticな展開をどっか期待してんだろ
Spilling out words of love and hate, somewhere hoping for a dramatic twist.
君もyes, yes息を呑んで 採点はそこにあんだろ
You too, holding your breath with a yes, yes, the score is right there, isn't it?
headshot騒ぐ想いも その心撃ち抜いてさ
Shooting through that heart with turbulent headshot thoughts,
まだ見ぬ糸を引いて 黒幕のお出ましさ
Pulling unseen threads as the mastermind makes an appearance.
触れたら壊れてしまった
Broke the moment it was touched.
間違っていく様子を黙った
Kept quiet as things went wrong.
僕ら全員無垢でありました
We were all once pure and innocent.
いつの間にか怪獣になったんだ
Before we knew it, we became monsters.
その全てを肯定しないと前に進めないか
Can't we move forward without affirming all of it?
「まあ君にはきっと無理なんだ」
"Well, you surely can't do it."
「だから君にはきっと無理なんだ」
"That's why you surely can't do it."
いつの間にかがいやになったんだ そんなゲームばっかり飛ばしてきたんだ
Before we knew it, we got sick of it, skipping all those games.
みんな必死に自分を守って 救いの手を待っているのさ
Everyone desperately protects themselves, waiting for a helping hand.
考えたくはないよ
I don't want to think about it.
馬鹿になってたいもんね
I'd rather just act foolish.
ずっと僕は何者にもなれなくて だから今最前線に立って
I could never become anyone, so now I stand on the front lines,
その旗は高く舞って
With that flag flying high.
劣勢頼る相棒 言葉すら必要ないよ
My partner relying on adversity, we don't even need words.
dramaticな展開をどっか期待してんだろ
You're hoping for some dramatic twist somewhere, right?
君もyes, yes息を呑んで 再会を誓い合って
You too, holding your breath with a yes, yes, swearing to meet again.
one chanceしかない僕の 一瞬をかけるのさ
Risking the single instant of my only chance.
climaxみたいな手に汗を握るのさ
Clutching our sweaty hands like a climax.
諦めかけた人の前にアンタは いつも嘲笑うようにお出ましさ
Before those about to give up, you always appear with a sneer.
君にはどんな風に見えてるんだい
How does this all look to you?
呼吸を整えてさ
Regulating your breathing,
さあ
Come on,
ずっと僕は何者にもなれなくて
I could never become anyone at all,
僕ら今さざめき合って
As we now murmur together,
延長戦サレンダーして メーデー淡い愛想
Surrendering in overtime, Mayday, faint friendliness,
垂れ流し言の愛憎 dramaticな展開をどっか期待してんだろ
Spilling out words of love and hate, somewhere hoping for a dramatic twist.
君もyes, yes息を呑んで 採点はそこにあんだろ
You too, holding your breath with a yes, yes, the score is right there, isn't it?
headshot騒ぐ想いも その心撃ち抜いてさ
Shooting through that heart with turbulent headshot thoughts,
まだ見ぬ糸を引いて 黒幕のお出ましさ
Pulling unseen threads as the mastermind makes an appearance.
その目に映るのは
What's reflected in those eyes
触れたら壊れてしまった
Broke the moment it was touched.
間違っていく様子を黙った
Kept quiet as things went wrong.
僕ら全員無垢でありました
We were all once pure and innocent.
いつの間にか怪獣になったんだ
Before we knew it, we became monsters.
その全てを...
All of it...
頭でわかっては嘆いた
I knew it all too well and sighed,
転がっていく様子を嘲笑った
mocking the way things kept rolling down.
ブレーメンを目指して旅立った
Heading to Bremen, set on a journey,
ロバ、犬、猫たち。
a donkey, a dog, and cats.
自分のかがやける場所を求めて歩く足取りは、不安と期待の風が吹くけれど、
Seeking a place where they could truly shine, their footsteps walked through winds of anxiety and hope,
同時に今まで感じたことのない高揚感と自由に満ちていました。
yet they were simultaneously filled with an unprecedented sense of exhilaration and freedom.
さあ進もう！
Now, let's move forward!
愉快な声が聞こえる方へ。
Toward where joyful voices can be heard.
楽しい農場、楽しい農場
A fun farm, a fun farm,
楽しいだけの農場
just a fun little farm!
愉快な農場、愉快な農場、愉快なだけの農場
A cheerful farm, a cheerful farm, just a cheerful little farm!
お父様ポカポカ、楽しくて愉快なだけの農場
Father is warm and cozy, a farm of pure joy and cheer!
とってものどかで良い歌ですね
That's a very peaceful and lovely song.
これはほら勿体ない言葉、でも…
That's such a wasteful thing to say, but...
本当にそう思いますか？
Do you really think so?
こここここんなもんじゃない
This isn't all there is to it—
ほとばしる骨のミュージック
music surging straight from the bones!
こここここんな田舎で
In a countryside town like this,
くすぶってる場合じゃねえぜ
there's no time to just sit and smolder!
もっと自分を魂したい
I want to pour more of my soul into this,
もっと自由な音楽で
with even freer music,
ほらドライブかけたら止まらないぜ Rock and roll!
and once we hit the drive, there's no stopping! Rock and roll!
あの、本当はこういう曲が好きなんですけど！
Um, actually, I really love songs like this!
デイジー、お隣のブレーメンですが
Daisy, that's Bremen next door, but—
よかったら共に参るか？
Would you like to come along if you'd like?
すぐ行こう！一起見してるぜ
Let's go right now! We're checking it out together!
このサウンドが分かるのか？
Can you understand this sound?
おうYes! それじゃあ取り込んでやるぜ
Oh, yes! Then we'll absorb it right in!
ブレーメン Yeah!
Bremen, yeah!
ブレーメンへ行こう　なりたい自分に正直に
Let's go to Bremen, true to the self we want to be,
流れる世界を目指してゆこう　一緒に！
aiming for a flowing world, together!
ねえみんな、このお店に入らない？ひと息ついたら作戦会議をしましょう。
Hey everyone, why don't we go into this shop? Let's take a breather and hold a strategy meeting.
ここはなんだか吠えるのにちょうどいい場所だ。あおーん！
This place somehow feels just right for howling. Awooo!
歳にメインディッシュか？漆黒の闇に光る天使の微笑みを掴むためのレシピエントを奏でたい。
Main dish for our age? I want to play a recipient to capture the angel's smile shining in the pitch-dark night.
ドキドキ Rock and roll! はいベイビーベイビーベイビーベイビーベイビー
Heart-pounding rock and roll! Yes, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby!
なかなか面白そうな連中じゃないか。
Aren't you quite an interesting bunch?
えっ？あなた誰？ 変態？変態って初めて見た！
Huh? Who are you? A pervert? It's my first time seeing a pervert!
変態じゃない！
I'm not a pervert!
私こそは強きをくじき弱きを助ける正義の大海賊だ！
I am none other than the righteous great pirate who crushes the strong and helps the weak!
暗闇まぎれ、ちょうだいする秘宝は財宝をすべて狙い付けるわ
Slipping through the dark, the treasures I'll claim are aimed at all riches.
金持ちども、それだけが私の流儀
You rich folks, that alone is my style.
分かったら有り金全部置いいてさっさと立ち去りな！
If you understand, leave all your money behind and get lost quickly!
そんなこと言われても私たちお金なんて何もないで
Even if you say that, we don't have any money at all—
え？そうなの？
Eh? Is that so?
いや騙されないぞ！貧乏人がそんなに楽しそうに笑えるはずがない！
No, I won't be fooled! Poor people couldn't possibly laugh so happily!
貧しかった幼い頃、おなかをすかせた私は絶望の底にいた。
In my impoverished childhood, hungry, I was at the depths of despair.
え、なんか始まっちゃった…
Eh, something's starting up...
だからこそ私はそんな人たちを笑顔にしたかった！それなのに…
That's precisely why I wanted to make people like that smile! And yet...
ああっ、それだけなのに！なぜこんなに胸が痛む？なぜ私はこんな方法しか知らないんだ？
Ah, just that! Why does my chest hurt so much? Why do I only know such a method?
人を笑顔にする方法…
A way to make people smile...
ふ、疑問だな。
Hmph, that's a question.
僕にも分かってきたかも。でも、一人じゃできないだろ？
I might be starting to understand too. But you can't do it alone, right?
だから私たちと…
That's why with us...
ブレーメンへ行こう！
Let's go to Bremen!
僕らだけじゃない笑顔のため
For smiles that aren't just our own,
歌おう歌おう、きっとできるはずさ行こう
let's sing and sing, we can definitely do it, let's go!
ブレーメン！
Bremen!
生活の偽造 いつも通り通り過ぎて
A forged life, passing by just as usual.
1回言った「わかった」戻らない
The 'I understand' I said once won't come back.
確信犯でしょ? 夕食中に泣いた後
You planned it, right? After crying during dinner,
君は笑っていた
you were smiling.
「私もそうだよ」って 偽りの気持ちが重なって
'Me too,' our false feelings piled up,
吐いて黙って ずっと溜まってく
swallowing our words, keeping it all bottled up.
何が何でも 面と向かって「さようなら」する資格もないままで僕は
I don't even have the right to face you and say goodbye no matter what.
灰に潜り 拍動を噛み 白昼夢の中でガンガン砕いた
Diving into the ashes, biting the heartbeat, smashing through a daydream.
でも壊れない 止まってくれない
Yet it won't break, it won't stop.
「本当」を知らないまま進むのさ
Moving forward without ever knowing the 'truth'.
このまま奪って 隠して 忘れたい
I just want to steal it, hide it, and forget it.
分かり合う 1つもなくても 会って「ごめん」って 返さないでね
Even with nothing to understand, don't meet me and say 'I'm sorry'.
形の無い 言葉はいらないから 消えない後遺症
I don't need intangible words—just an everlasting aftereffect.
「なんでも受け入れる。」と言ったきり もう戻ることはない
Ever since you said 'I accept anything,' there's no turning back.
デタラメでも 僕のためじゃなくて君に守られた
Even if it's nonsense, not for my sake, I was protected by you.
目も口も 意味がないほどに
To the point where eyes and mouth have no meaning.
どこ見ても どこに居ても 開かない
No matter where I look or where I am, it won't open.
白昼夢の中でガンガン砕いた
Smashing through a daydream with all my might.
でも壊れない 止まってくれない
Yet it won't break, it won't stop.
演じ続けるのなら
If I'm to keep acting this out.
このまま奪って 隠して 忘れたい
I just want to steal it, hide it, and forget it.
分かり合う 1つもなくても 会って「ごめん」って 返さないでね
Even with nothing to understand, don't meet me and say 'I'm sorry'.
形の無い 言葉はいらないから すがりついて叫んで
I don't need intangible words, clinging and screaming...
どこ見ても どこに居ても 開かない
No matter where I look or where I am, it won't open.
灰に潜り 拍動を噛み 白昼夢の中でガンガン砕いた
Diving into the ashes, biting the heartbeat, smashing through a daydream.
でも壊れない 止まってくれない
Yet it won't break, it won't stop.
演出続けるのなら
If I'm to keep staging this.
このまま奪って 隠して 忘れたい
I just want to steal it, hide it, and forget it.
分かり合う 1つもなくても 会って「ごめん」って 返さないでね
Even with nothing to understand, don't meet me and say 'I'm sorry'.
形の無い 言葉はいらないから 消えない後遺症
I don't need intangible words—just an everlasting aftereffect.
「なんでも受け入れる。」と言ったきり もう戻ることはない
Ever since you said 'I accept anything,' there's no turning back.
すがりついて 叫んで 朝はない
Clinging and screaming, there is no morning.
笑って 転んで 惜しけない
Laughing and falling down, with no regrets.
誰のせいでもないこと 誰のせいにしたくて
Wanting to blame someone for something that is nobody's fault.
「僕って いるのかな?」 本当はわかっているんだ
'Do I even exist?' Deep down, I actually know.
見放されても 信じてしまうよ
Even if I'm abandoned, I still end up believing.
このまま奪って 隠して 忘れたい
I just want to steal it, hide it, and forget it.
このまま奪って 隠して 話したい
I just want to steal it, hide it, and talk about it.
分かり合う 1つもなくても 会って「ごめん」って 返さないでね
Even with nothing to understand, don't meet me and say 'I'm sorry'.
疑うだけの 僕をどうして?
Why do you treat me like this, when I only doubt?
救いきれない 嘘はいらないから
I don't need unsaveable lies.
晴れた
Clearing up,
レイラ
Leila.
今宵も頭上では
Tonight, overhead,
綺麗な満月がキラキラ
a beautiful full moon sparkles brilliantly,
幸せそうに世界を照らしている
happily illuminating the world.
当の私は出来そこないでどうしようもなくて
I'm completely useless, just a good-for-nothing,
夜明け夢見ては地べた這いずり回ってる
dreaming at dawn, crawling all over the ground.
逃げ出したいが逃げ出せない
I want to run away, but I can't escape,
明るい未来は見えないね
and I can't see a bright future anywhere.
それでも誰かに見つけて欲しくて夜空見上げて叫んでいる
Still, I want someone to find me, so I look up at the night sky and scream.
ねぇ それでもあなたに見つけて欲しくて
Hey, still, I want you to find me,
蝶のように舞い上がるの 欠けた翼で飛んだ 醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
soaring like a butterfly, flying with chipped wings—a crescent moon, child of an ugly star.
今宵も頭上では
Tonight, overhead,
綺麗な満月がゆらゆら 誰かの腕に抱かれて眠っている
a beautiful full moon sways gently, sleeping in someone's arms.
当の私は一人の夜に押し潰されては 誰にも見えない夜闇這いずり回ってる
I am crushed by lonely nights, crawling through invisible darkness.
それでも誰にも負けたくなくて
Still, not wanting to lose to anyone,
宇宙の隅でもがいている
I'm struggling in the corner of the universe.
追いつきたいや 追い越したい ああ 夢見たような世界
I want to catch up, I want to overtake... Ah, in a world like a dream.
ねぇ それでも誰かと比べてばかり 周りを見ては立ち止まって 欠けたものを探した
Hey, still, constantly comparing myself to others, looking around and stopping in my tracks, I searched for what was missing.
そんな自分を変えたい
I want to change such a self.
それでもあなたと同じ景色がまた見たいから
Still, because I want to see the same scenery with you again,
泣き出したいとても 投げ出したいとても 諦めたりはできない
even if I want to cry, even if I want to give up, I cannot give up.
それでもあなたに見つかるように サナギは強く手を伸ばすの
Still, so that you can find me, I bravely reach out my hand strongly,
欠けたものを抱きしめて 願いを放つよ ミカヅキ
embracing what is missing and releasing my wish, Mikazuki.
それでも誰かに見つけて欲しくて
Still, wanting someone to find me,
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
I look up at the night sky and scream.
泣き出したいけど泣き出さない もう後戻りなどできない
I want to start crying, but I won't, I can't turn back anymore.
ねぇ それでもあなたに見つけて欲しくて 蝶のように舞い上がるの
Hey, still, wanting you to find me, soaring like a butterfly—
欠けた翼で飛ぶよ 醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
flying with chipped wings, Mikazuki, the child of an ugly star.
光を放ったミカヅキ
Mikazuki that emitted light.
今宵も頭上では綺麗な満月がキラキラ
Tonight too, overhead, a beautiful full moon shines brilliantly.
次は君の番だと笑っている
Smiling as if to say, "Now it's your turn."
Welcome to Bremen Music Festival!!
楽しかったパーティもいよいよクライマックス！
The climax of this fun party is finally here!
次次は飛びり参加で一色のユニットが登場です！
Next, the single-unit group appearance!
石油の国のプリンセス ロア
The princess of the oil kingdom, Lora!
大地を揺らすミラクルボイス 戌神ころね
The miracle voice that shakes the earth, Korone!
暗黒世界の探求者 猫又おかゆ
The cat-eared searcher of the underworld, Okayu!
俺の音楽を聴け！ 桃鈴ねね
Listen to my music, Kiara!
音楽の力で
With the power of music,
奇跡を起こす
we create a miracle,
ブレーメン動物チーム！
the Bremen Animal Team!
いくつもの出会いが私に教えてくれた
Many encounters have taught me...
自分で作る日々が私を私にさせる
The days I shape myself make me who I am.
この声だって 誰かをきっと勇気づけてる
Even this voice is surely encouraging someone,
だから恐れず 精一杯の僕でいよう
so without fear, let's be our best selves.
止まれないような空音だって
In a sky where we can't stop,
夢と呼べる場所がある
there is a place we can call a dream.
自由な羽ばたきで巻き起こす風も
Even the wind stirred by free wings
いつか誰かの憧れに変えてみせるから
will someday turn into someone's longing.
歌おう ミュージックパズルは 響け届け世界へ
Let's sing, music puzzle! Resonate and reach the world,
この魔法の力信じて 輝き僕らの歌
believing in this magic power, our shining song.
やっと見つけた 笑顔の届け方
At last, I found how to deliver a smile,
簡単な言葉ばかりじゃないけれど
though it's not just simple words.
声を合わせれば きっとできる
If we match our voices, we surely can do it.
試してみて この呪文を
Try out this spell!
さあ 一緒に
Now, together!
歌おう ミュージックパズルは 響け届け世界へ
Let's sing, music puzzle! Resonate and reach the world,
この魔法で変わるすべて 目に焼き付けて
burning everything that changes with this magic into our eyes.
歌おう ミュージックパズルは 誰もひとりじゃないさ
Let's sing, music puzzle! No one is alone, so
この声で繋ぐ心よ 大空を超えて
this heart connected by our voice, crossing the open sky!
僕らの意味を 教えてくれる
who teaches us our meaning,
温かな音の波 重なって
warm waves of sound overlapping,
いつでも夢を 与えてくれる
giving us dreams at any time—
それが音楽だから
that is what music is!
ブレーメン
Bremen...
ブレーメンへ行こう
Let's go to Bremen!
あらためてアキロゼ生誕祭2024をご覧の皆さんありがとうございます！
To everyone watching the Aki Rosenthal Birthday Festival 2024, thank you so much!
おっと、まだ終わりじゃないから最後までチャンネルはそのままで
Hold on, it's not over yet, so keep your channel right here until the very end!
ということで今年はなんとついにアキラさんのオスタープロジェクトさんに
So this year, unbelievably, OSTER project created
オリジナルミュージカルを作っていただきましたー！どう、どうだったかな？
an original musical for us! How... how was it?
みんなからの感想いっぱい聞けたら嬉しいので
We'd be so happy to hear all your impressions,
ハッシュタグアキロゼ生誕祭2024をつけていっぱいポストしてね
so please post lots with the hashtag #AkiRofeBirthday2024!
エゴサで探しに行くからね待っててよ！
I'll be searching for them via ego-search, so wait for it!
そしてチャンネル登録 今回出演メンバーも含めて
And subscription, including this time's cast members,
ぜひまだの人格よろしくおねがいします！
please subscribe if you haven't yet!
メンバーシップ登録してくれてる人もありがとう！
And thank you to those who subscribed to membership!
実はこのあとメンバー限定でアフタライヴが と言いたいところだったんだけど
Actually, right after this, for members only, an after-live was what I wanted to say,
本編に全部詰め込んでしましまいましてライブはないです
but we crammed everything into the main feature so there is no live.
ただ未公開のオフショットとかを公開予定なのでぜひメンバー登録して待っててね
However, we plan to release unreleased off-shots, so please register for membership!
そして明日に今回のミュージカルの制作秘話とか
And tomorrow, I'd love to share stories about making this musical,
裏話とかそのへんの感想をいっぱいぎゅっと詰めて
behind-the-scenes tales, and all my thoughts packed tightly into one stream,
お話しできたらいいなって思ってるので、その配信もお楽しみに。
so please look forward to that stream as well!
ということで皆さんおまちかね！
With that said, everyone, the moment you've been waiting for!
グッズ告知タイムです！
It's merchandise announcement time!
生誕記念グッズ頑張って作らせていただきました！
We worked hard to make these birthday commemorative goods!
こちら、ドン！
Here they are, boom!
アキロゼ誕生日記念2024のグッズは
The merchandise for Aki Rosenthal's 2024 Birthday
ブレーメンの音楽隊をイメージして作らせていただきました。
was designed around the theme of the Bremen Town Musicians from the musical!
まずは「Fantasia of Bremen リバーシブルトートバッグ」！
First up is the "Fantasia of Bremen Reversible Tote Bag"!
イラストはカロ先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Karo-sensei.
ブレーメンの音楽隊の世界から飛び出すアキロゼ＆マスコットを描いていただいてます。
It features Aki Rosenthal and her mascot stepping out of the Bremen musical's world.
今回は普段使いもできるようにリバーシブルデザインをしているので、
It has a reversible design so you can use it every day,
推し活でアピールしたい時もおしゃれに使いたい時もぜひぜひいっぱい使ってくれると嬉しいです。
whether you're showing off your oshi love or styling a casual look. I'd be so happy if you use it a lot!
超可愛い！
Super cute!
続いて、「Fantasia of Bremen アクセサリースタンド」！
Next is the "Fantasia of Bremen Accessory Stand"!
ブレーメンといえばシルエットが特徴的だったりするので、シルエットのデザインのグッズを作ってみました！すごい可愛い感じに仕上がってます。
Since Bremen is known for its distinct silhouettes, I made a goods item with silhouette designs! It turned out super cute.
ま、アクセサリーに限らずいろんなものをかけたりとか、デスク周りや玄関周りに置いても可愛いと思います。
Not just for accessories, you can hang various things on it, and I think it'd look cute on your desk or by the entryway!
さらに、「Fantasia of Bremen ピンバッチ」！
Furthermore, the "Fantasia of Bremen Pin Badge"!
さっきのバッグとかアクセサリースタンドとかにつけてもかわいいです。
It's super cute attached to the tote bag or accessory stand I mentioned earlier.
そしてそして、アキロゼぬいぐるみ マーチングver.が遂に登場！
And last but not least, the Aki Rosenthal Plushie (Marching Ver.) is finally here!
こちらアキロゼ5周年ライブのときに発表したオリジナル曲「キミにまつわる運命事情」のジャケットイラストになっている星川子先生デザインのマーチング衣装がぬいぐるみになっちゃいました！どのぽんぽふー？
This plushie features the marching outfit designed by Hoshikawa Ko-sensei from the jacket illustration of her original song "Fate Matters Concerning You," announced at her 5th-anniversary live! Look at that fluffy pom-pom!
これもね、トートバッグにつけたりしても可愛いし、ぜひいっぱい楽しんで可愛がってください。
It's cute attached to your tote bag too, so please enjoy it and give it lots of love!
さらに、今回もボイス出ます！「生誕祭のあと～お耳はむはむ～」というようなちょっと気になるタイトルになってるんですが、
Also, we have a voice pack coming out this time too! It has a somewhat intriguing title: "After the Birthday Party ~ Nibbling Your Ears ~,"
今回もアキロゼ自分で書きました！
and this time I wrote it all myself!
ということは、それすなわちちょっとドキドキが強めかも知れません。
Which means... it might be a bit extra heart-pounding.
ASMRボイスをたっぷり楽しんでもらうためにバイノーラル録音で収録させていただきました！ぜひお楽しみに。
It was recorded in binaural sound so you can fully enjoy the ASMR voice! Please look forward to it.
今回のグッズフルセットご購入予定の方はいらっしゃいますか？いらっしゃいますよね？なんと特典があります！
Are there any of you planning to buy the full merchandise set? Of course there are, right? There is a special bonus!
カロ先生描き下ろしイラストポストカードがついてきます！しかも数量限定バージョンのほうにはアキロゼ直筆サイン＆直筆メッセージ入り！
A postcard with a newly drawn illustration by Karo-sensei is included! What's more, the limited quantity version features an autographed signature & handwritten message from Aki Rosenthal!
直筆サインはついちゃうよ！数量限定を超えてしまうと箔押し複製サインになっちゃうので早い者勝ちです。
It comes with a real signature! If it exceeds the limited quantity, it turns into a foil-stamped replica signature, so it's first come, first served.
この後配信終了後22時から販売開始になるので、ぜひ今のうちにチェックチェック！
Sales start at 22:00 right after this stream ends, so make sure to check it out right away!
改めてアキロゼ生誕祭2024応援してくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you once again for supporting the Aki Rosenthal Birthday Celebration 2024!
エンドロールでは今回出演してくれたみんなとたくさんお話をしたので、ぜひ最後までご注目ください。メンバー限定の未公開オフショットもお楽しみに！メンバー登録も待ってるよ。
In the end credits, we had a lot of chats with everyone who appeared, so please check it out until the very end. Look forward to the unreleased member-only off-shots too! I'm waiting for you to join as a member.
制作秘話や裏話は明日改めてするのでそちらもお楽しみにね。それではみんな今日はアキロゼ生誕祭2024 3Dライブ見に来てくれてありがと！これからもいっぱい応援してね！
The behind-the-scenes stories will be shared tomorrow, so look forward to that as well. Thank you everyone for coming to watch the Aki Rosenthal Birthday Celebration 2024 3D Live today! Please keep cheering me on!
それでは今回出演してくれたゲストの紹介をしていきましょう！
Now then, let's introduce our guest who performed today!
まずは大きな犬役やってくれたころね！
First is Korone, who played the big dog!
はーい！楽しかったー！楽しかったね！楽しかった！うん！このライブの、このライブの犬、ゲームアズの犬神ころねです！よろしくお願いします！
Hi! It was fun! So fun, right? It was fun! Yeah! This live's—this live's dog, Inugami Korone from GAMERS! Nice to meet you!
はーい、もうこれは今回チュートぴったりのでころねにしかできないような役だったんだけどね。そうだよね！犬と言えばだもんね。
Yeah, this was a role that only Korone could pull off so perfectly for this show. That's right! Because we're talking about dogs, after all.
でも犬と言えばていうか犬だもんね。そうだよ、犬だもんね犬そのものだから。
But not just like a dog, you literally are a dog. Right, it's a dog, so it's literally a dog itself.
いるかそんなもんって感じだったんだけど、
"Do I even need this?" is what I thought, but...
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
あきちゃんがね、色々教えてくれたりとか、一緒にね、あのやってくれたりとかして、
Aki-chan taught me a lot and even did it with me together, so...
なんとか、なんとかできた！
I somehow, I somehow managed it!
なんとかできた！
I somehow managed it!
いやー！
Man!
できてさ、可愛いし、最高だって思ったよ。嬉しい！
I pulled it off, and it was so cute and amazing. I'm so happy!
でも楽しかったね。
It was also a lot of fun, you know.
ね、コロネのお気に入りポイントとか、ここ見てポイントみたいなのってあったりするの？
Hey, do you have any favorite parts or highlights of yours, Korone?
お気に入りは、やっぱりコロネが一番最初にあきちゃんに出会うじゃん？
My favorite is how Korone is the very first one to meet Aki-chan, right?
うんうんうん。そこでその、なんかコロネが悩んでる時にあきちゃんが「ほいってみて」っていうシーンがあるんだけど、
Yeah, yeah, yeah. And in that scene, when Korone is troubled, Aki-chan says, "Hey, try this."
そこ度のなんか、なんか友情の芽生えじゃないけど、そこ度のね、あきちゃんとの絡みがすごい好きだからさ、またみんなに見てほしいです。
There's this kind of budding friendship, and I love my interactions with Aki-chan so much, so I'd love for everyone to see it again.
やー、嬉しい。あそこの、「わお」って褒めてくれるところの、大好きなんだよね。
Aww, I'm so happy. I love that part where you praise me with a "Wah!"
そう、ほいってみて、わおって、あそこにもうテーテーだから、
Yeah, "Hey, try this" and "Wah"—that part is just so teete!
テーテーなの？
Is it teete?
テーテーなのか？えっ、テーテーではないか？
Is it even teete? Well, maybe not teete—
あっ、テーテーというかさ、可愛くて、あきろぜの大好きなポイントだよ、ここ。
Wait, it's so cute, and it's AkiRose's favorite point, right here!
え、嬉しい。ね、めちゃ楽しかった。ありがとー！
Yay, I'm happy. Man, it was so much fun! Thank you!
はい、じゃあ、それでは、コロネありがとねー！
All right, then, Korone, thank you so much!
あきちゃん、誕生日本当ににおめでとう！
Aki-chan, happy, happy birthday!
あー、ありがとう。
Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
またねー！
See you later!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
それでは続いて、中二病の猫又おおかゆやってくれたおおかゆー！
And next up, Nekomata Okayu, who played our Chunibyo character!
はーい、もぐもぐおおかゆ、どうも猫又おおかゆです。
Hi, Mogu Mogu Okayu, it's Nekomata Okayu.
おおかゆー！あきちゃーん！
Okayu! Aki-chan!
いや、一緒にオカユとミュージカルやりたかったんだよ。
Man, I really wanted to do a musical with Okayu.
いや、私もさ、毎年あきちゃんがミュージカルやってるの見てて、いつか私も参加したいなと思ってたから、今回こうやって声かけてもらえてすっごく嬉しかったよ。
Well, I see Aki-chan doing musicals every year, and I always thought I wanted to join someday, so I was super happy when you invited me this time.
えー、うっすきー。
Aww, I love you.
ぼくもすっきー。
I love you too.
え、おおかゆはさ、今日やってみてどうだった？
So, Okayu, how was it doing it today?
いやもうなんか、僕は「よーし、かっこいい猫の役だぞ」と思って、もういっぱいかっこつけてやってたから、
Well, you know, I was thinking, "Alright, I'm playing a cool cat role," so I was putting on a lot of cool airs while doing it.
最後にあきちゃんが私の名前呼ぶときに、なんか「中二病猫みたいな」って言ってて、「えっ」ってなったんですけど、
Then at the very end, when Aki-chan called my name, she said something like, "Like a Chunibyo cat," and I was like, "Huh?!"
あきちゃ？
Aki-chan?
まあちょっとね、途中の歌の歌詞とかをよく見てもらうと、結構なんか中二病あふれる…
Well, you know, if you look closely at the lyrics of the song midway through, it's actually pretty full of Chunibyo...
えっ！
What?!
そうだったの！？めちゃくちゃかっこいい猫だと思ってやってたよ！
Is that so?! I thought I was playing a super cool cat!
まああえて中二病の猫だよとはおおかゆに伝えなかった。
Well, I didn't deliberately tell Okayu that she was a Chunibyo cat.
お、いま、いま初めて知った！今！
Wait, I'm finding out about this just now!
いやでもそのかっこつけがね、やっぱかっこいい感じになってたから、まあよかったんじゃないかな？
Well, but that posing and stuff made you look really cool, so I guess it turned out fine, right?
よかった。
That's true.
じゃあ、いっか！
Oh well, then!
じゃあいいよ！じゃあいい！
That's fine! It's fine!
え、なんか二人でさ、かけあってハモるとこめっちゃ好きなんだよね。
And you know, harmonizing and singing together was so much fun.
わかるー！
I know!
そう、歌っててめちゃ気持ちよかったよー！
Yeah, singing it felt so amazing!
えーそこはみんなにもっといっぱい聞いてほしいところだよね。
Yeah, that's definitely a part I want everyone to listen to more.
ねー、いっぱい聞いてほしいー！
Right, I want them to listen a lot!
はい、じゃあ今日は一緒にやってくれてありがとう、楽しかったよ！
Right, so thank you so much for joining me today, it was fun!
こちらこそだよ、めちゃ楽しかった！
The feeling is mutual, it was super fun!
あきちゃん、今日はお誕生日おめでとうだよ！
Aki-chan, happy, happy birthday today!
ありがとうー、もふもふ、あきと、もふもふー！
Thank you! Mofumofu Aki, and Mofumofu!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
それでは続いて、鶏役をやってくれたキアラ！
And next up, Kiara, who played the chicken role!
キケアレテー！イェーイ！イェーイ！
Kikiare! Yay! Yay!
ホロライブEnglishの高梨キアラです。
I'm Takanashi Kiara from Hololive English.
鶏役だったけど、これは鶏だったということじゃないですからね。
I played a chicken, but that doesn't mean I actually was a chicken, you know.
これでも不祝長です。
Even so, I'm a Phoenix.
不祝長ですよ。
I'm a Phoenix.
不祝長のほ？
You mean the Phoenix?
不祝長だよ！
I'm a Phoenix!
鶏じゃない？
Not a chicken?
鶏、まあ今日だけにわとり！
Chicken... well, just for today, a chicken!
今日だけにわとりね。そう。
Just for today, a chicken, right.
いや、すごい楽しかったよキアラ一緒にやってくれてありがとね。
Man, it was so much fun, Kiara. Thank you so much for doing this with me.
イェーイ！もちろんもちろん！
Yay! Of course, of course!
ミュージカルやってみてどうだった？
How was it doing a musical?
うーん、なんか繋がってる物語が、あるのがすごくいいと思ったし、なんか感動する演奏がとてもいいなと思ったのと、
Well, I thought it was really great that there was a connected storyline, and I felt that the touching musical performances were wonderful.
なんか頭の中でミュージカルをイメージしてやってみたので、すごく楽しかったよ！
Also, I imagined a musical in my head while doing it, so I had a lot of fun!
いや、もうキアラのパートはね、とってもね、この曲の中でも面白いパートだと思ったし、うんうんうん、面白かった！
Yeah, Kiara's part is, you know, such an entertaining part of this song, and it was so funny!
そう、キアラが恋でしょ？
Yeah, Kiara was in love, right?
うん、うん、そう。ベイビー、ベイビー、ベイビー、ベイビー、ベイビー、ベイビー、ベイビー！
Yeah, yeah, right. "Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby!"
ギターも引いてたし、もちろんギター引けます。
You were playing the guitar too. Of course I can play guitar.
嘘、完璧！ありがとう。
"No way, perfect." Thank you.
うそ？
Really?
嘘。
No.
うそ、すごい！
No way, amazing!
でも本当に一緒にねやってくれて…
But really, thank you so much for joining me...
えて嬉しいよ、ありがとね。
I'm so glad, thank you!
うん！ありがとう！
Yeah! Thank you!
天才、天才、アキ先輩は天才！
Genius, genius, Aki-senpai is a genius!
いや、そんな褒めても何も出ないよ～！
No, even if you praise me like that, nothing's coming out!
じゃあ、うん。
Well, yeah.
やら、うん、またなんか一緒にやろうね。
Yeah, let's do something together again.
やろう！
Let's do it!
ありがとう呼んでくれて！
Thanks for inviting me!
お誕生日おめでとー！おめでとー！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅ、ちゅちゅちゅ、
Mwah mwah mwah mwah mwah,
バイバ～イ！バイバ～イ！
bye-bye! Bye-bye!
テンション高いな！
Her energy is so high!
それでは続いて、泥棒役やってくれたマリンちゃーん！
Next up, playing the role of the thief, Marine-chan!
はーい！
Hii!
あほーい！
Ahoi!
宝船海賊団船長の宝船マリンです！
I'm Houshou Marine, captain of the Houshou Pirate Crew!
やったー！
Yay!
やった！やり切った！やり切ったねマジで！
Yay! I did it! I really pulled it off!
マジでハマり役だったと思うんだけど、今回やってみてどうだった？
I think I was a great fit for the role, but how was it doing it this time?
いや船長、なんか初めて気づいたんだけど、なんかこういうのすごい好きかもしれないわ。
Well, Captain, I just realized... I think I really love this kind of thing.
え、本当は？え、なんかめちゃくちゃいい経験できた、本当にたるたるありがとう！
Really? Man, I had such a great experience, Tarutaru, thank you so much!
たるたるとか呼んでくれるの実は嬉しいんだよ。
Actually, it makes me happy when you call me Tarutaru.
あ、ちゃんと呼びますよ、もちろん。
Of course, I'll call you that properly.
いや、なんかやっぱりミュージカルっていう経験自体もちろんね、当然なくて、
But you know, having the musical experience itself, of course I didn't have that,
なんかこういうすごいハマり役をね、もらえて、もうすっごい楽しくて、セリフ言うのがもうめちゃくちゃまず楽しくて、
but getting such a great fitting role, it was so much fun, just saying the lines was so much fun,
歌もなんかすごい船長が好きなタイプのちょっと何系って言うんだろ、アハン系なの？
and the song is... Captain's favorite type, what genre is it? Ahon-style?
アハン系よ。やらせてもらって、もうみんなでね、大団円へ迎えてもマジで感動しちゃったわ。本当に楽しかったです。
Ahon-style. Getting to do that, and heading towards the grand finale with everyone, I was really moved. It was really fun.
よかった！実はね、今回ミュージカルをやろうと思って、色々考えた、最初からいろんなストーリー考えたりとかしてたんだけど、
I'm glad! Actually, when I thought about doing a musical this time, I thought about various stories from the beginning,
いや、泥棒役はマリンちゃんしかいないなと思って。
and I thought Marine-chan is the only one who can play the thief.
いや、ありがとうございます！そうですよね、海賊なんだからもう、ようやく生き延びてきたかって感じで、
Thank you very much! That's right, since I'm a pirate, I've finally survived, so
もうマリンがやりえないすよ、海賊じゃなくて泥棒はね。
Marine couldn't possibly do anything else—not a pirate, but a thief.
マリーがありえないで全部初めての台付けとかも、そういうアハン系で作ったから、
Marine being impossible, and creating all those first-time lines with that Ahon-style,
ちょっとマリバコみたいな動きがあったりしてね。
and having some Maribako-like movements,
その様子も気づいたやっぱり。
I noticed that too, of course!
当たり前じゃないですか！
Isn't that obvious?!
これ100万回やった光景みたいな。感じてね。
It's like a scene I've seen a million times.
あーよかった！ありがとね！
Ah, I'm glad! Thank you!
本当に楽しかった！
It was really fun!
あ、そうだたるたる、お誕生日！お誕生日おめでとう！
Oh right, Tarutaru, happy birthday! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ついでみたいになっちゃったけど、おめでとう！
It ended up sounding like an afterthought, but congratulations!
ありがとうね！また呼んでくださいね！バイバ～イ！
Thank you! Please invite me again! Bye-bye!
それでは、今回語り部をやしてくれたポルポルー！
Next, playing the storyteller, Polporu!
はーい！どうも！ポルポルです！
Hii! Hello! It's Polporu!
サーカスもこうです！ポルポル！ありがとうポルポル！
The circus is like this too! Polporu! Thank you, Polporu!
あのさ、もうなんか、わかんない、今回すごい、また新しいのを持ってきたね、アキロゼ君。
You know, I don't know, this time you brought something totally new, Akirose-kun.
そうなんですよ。新しいの持ってきちゃいました、ポルポルカ先生。
That's right. I brought something new, Polpolka-sensei.
いやね、あのね、ポルカは正直、この立ち位置めちゃくちゃ美味しいものいただけで、ありがとうございました。
Well, you know, Polka is honestly... just getting to be in this position is super delicious, thank you very much.
まず自分のことになっちゃいましたが、ポルべえありがとうございました。
Even though it's about myself first, thank you so much for Porubei.
いやもうね、ポルポルは朗読も好きでね、結構やってるのも見てたし、合うよね。
Well, Polporu loves reading aloud, and doing it a lot I watched, and it fits so well.
もう合うんです！自分で思うけど、自分に言うのもなんだけど、あの、私しかできないなと思いながら、話し高々と。
It fits! I think to myself, though it's hard to say about myself, I thought "only I can do this," speaking proudly.
いや、ポルポルにしかできませんでした！ありがとうございました！
No, only Polporu could do it! Thank you very much!
いやもう本当に頭から、あの、中間のね、あの、あらすじみたいなのを語ってくれるところから、
Really, from the beginning, telling the synopsis in the middle,
と最後も歌でね、実は盛り上げてくれるっていうところもありまして。
and at the end, actually hyping it up with a song as well.
そうなんです。なんか、なんかさ、語り部なのにこんなにずっと楽し、まあ、でも、なんだろう、ちょっとね、みんなをね、こう引きながら見たりとかして、ちょっと
That's right. It's like, even though I'm the storyteller, I enjoyed it so much all through—well, but, somehow, pulling everyone in and watching...
本当に劇的にもすごく、ね、美味しかったな！
It was really dramatically delicious!
いや、本当においしかった！好きなのはマジでマリンのところ、っていうか、大泥棒さんのところですね。
Man, it was really delicious! My favorite part is really Marine's part, or rather, the great thief's part.
いやそこも音変わってさ、来るのがさ、マジでさ、見てるとうわあって
And the sound changes there, coming in, seriously, when watching it, wow!
いや、てんさん、ガッツだよね、やっぱね。いや、そう、多分ね、みんなもそう思ってると思うから、あそこでガラッと変わって、あのね、泥棒のターンになるっていう感じがすごく、好き、楽しいんです。
Well, Ten-san has guts, as expected. Yeah, so, everyone probably thinks that too, so changing completely there and turning into the thief's turn is something I really like and enjoy.
推しシーン！はい、ありがとうございます！
Favorite scene! Yes, thank you!
ま、全体もちろん最高です。こちらからもう以上ですって感じなんだけど。
Well, the whole thing is of course the best. That's all from me.
ちなみにアキロゼの生ーたポイントはですね、いっぱいあるんですけど、今回はアキロゼのセーターさんなんだけど、
By the way, Akirose's recommendation points, there are a lot, but this time it's Akirose's sweater-san,
びっくりするっていうね
You'd be surprised, right?
そう、まずお誕生日でしょ？
Right, first off, it's your birthday, right?
いやもう誕生日おめでとう！あれ、アキロゼ？
Wait, happy birthday already! Wait, Akirose?
あれ、ポルカ？みたいな
Wait, Polka? Something like that.
いやそれがまたね、びっくりでおもろかったんじゃないかなって思ってる
I thought it was surprising and funny in its own way.
それはみんな...
That's everyone...
そうだよね、ごめんね、そうだよね
That's right, sorry, that's right.
いやいやいや...でも素敵なプレゼントありがとうございました
No, no, no... but thank you so much for the wonderful present.
いやこちらこそおめでとうございます！
No, congratulations to you too!
はい、ありがとね、パルパル！
Yeah, thank you! Palparu!
みんなありがとー！改めてアキロゼおめでとう！
Thank you everyone! Once again, happy birthday, Akirose!
ありがとー！バイバイン、バイバイ！
Thank you! Baibain, bye-bye!